JOHN M. WISE

San Francisco, CA 94115 Phone: (415) 728-6648 | Email: jwise.ux@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/johnmwise | Portfolio: www.johnwisedesign.com

SUMMARY

UX Designer with an MFA in digital art & animation from Pratt Institute and a certificate in UX/UI from UC Berkeley. Skilled in user research, UX wireframing, prototyping, visual design, UI design, UX design thinking, communication, teamwork, creativity, and problem solving. Helped lead a team of UX designers to develop a novel bouquet customization tool, set to debut in December 2020 for a national flower delivery brand. Recognized and commissioned by the President of Pratt Institute while a graduate student; presented Pratt Circle award. Strengths lie in defining user needs, performing competitive analysis, and designing products that are beautiful, intuitive, and meet business needs. With a background in digital art & animation, my focus is on creative problem solving for users and business needs by employing UX research and design skills and to make the world a little bit better while doing so.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Technical: Programs – Figma, Adobe After Effects, Photoshop, Premiere, Illustrator, Invision, Github, Trello, Miro. Languages – HTML, CSS, Javascript. Libraries – Bootstrap, JQuery

UX/UI: User Centered Design Research, Competitive & Heuristic Analysis, UX Interviewing, Insight Synthesis, User Empathy, UX / Design Thinking, Prototyping & Wireframing, User Interface (UI) Development, User Testing, Micro-Interaction Implementation, Double Diamond Design Thinking

PROJECTS

Bokay: Online Customizable Bouquets | Bokay Slide Deck https://bit.ly/3hmvDQU

- Family Flowers is an online floral business based in Atlanta, Georgia. We partnered with them to develop BOKAY: a standalone online application where users create custom floral arrangements
- Helped lead a team of 4 UX/UI designers in qualitative/quantitative user research and UX design. Completed the double diamond design process and continue to iterate versions for the upcoming live site for mobile and desktop
- Developed UI tool prototype for creating a customizable bouguet
- Tools used: Figma, Google Suite

Precita Eyes Nonprofit RWD Redesign | Precita Eyes Slide Deck https://bit.ly/3j1U5HJ

 Precita Eyes is a San Francisco based nonprofit promoting and teaching the creation of community mural arts. Precita Eyes has been the heart of art in the Mission District for over 40 years and needed its online presence to reflect its importance in the community.
 We redesigned Precita Eyes' website to showcase their impactful work.

- Led a team of 5 UX/UI designers in user research, competitor analysis, and UX/UI design
- Developed visual design and prototype for a new RWD site based on research insights
- Tools: Figma, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe After Effects, Google Suite, Miro

California DMV Website Redesign | CA DMV Redesign Slide Deck https://bit.ly/31kIOfJ

- Confusing structure and overwhelming amounts of information make many government websites difficult to use. We redesigned the site to be more modern and welcoming while reorganizing the information architecture to improve usability.
- Led a team of 2 UX/UI designers in user research, competitor analysis and UX/UI design
- Tools: Figma, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe After Effects, Google Suite, Invision, Miro

EXPERIENCE

Junior Designer Gold Front Creative Studio

2019 – 2020

San Francisco, CA

Wore several hats while working at this boutique creative agency with hard-hitting productions and clients. Acted as motion designer, icon designer, UX researcher, presentation designer, and camera crew.

Key Accomplishments:

- Worked on award-winning short-film-ad <u>"The Exchange"</u> https://shortyawards.com/12th/giftnow-the-exchange
- Designed motion for Uniglo brand campaign

Motion Graphics Designer Farmuse Creative Studio

2019 - 2019

Nashville, TN

Created Motion Graphics, Titles, and Animation. Worked asynchronously with a remote team of producers, editors, and clients while meeting deadlines. Used strong communication skills to understand and reiterate clients' desires and needs.

Key Accomplishments:

- Developed animation and Title design for Cracker Barrel social media campaign
- Worked with the editor to streamline and condense videos for bite-size time constraints

Animator & Technician

2018 - 2019

Pratt Institute

Brooklyn, NY

Worked with several departments at the school while finishing an MFA. Worked throughout different departments connecting various schools within the Institute.

Key Accomplishments:

• Commissioned by the President of Pratt Institute to create animated work to represent her/the school to alumni, students, and staff

Art Department & PA Muhtayzik | Hoffer

2015 - 2016

San Francisco, CA

Worked as a PA, in the Art Department, and as model talent on many video productions and photographic ad campaigns. Utilized critical thinking, speed, efficiency, and communication to get any job done and make any shot possible that the director or producer required.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: UC Berkeley, Berkeley, CA

An intensive 24-week long boot camp dedicated to UX/UI and the double diamond design thinking process. Skills learned – Photoshop, Illustrator, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, User-Centric Design Research, Visual Prototyping & Wireframing, User Interface Development

MFA: Pratt Institute, Brooklyn, NY

Suggested 3-year program finished in 2 years dedicated to Digital Arts with an emphasis in Animation. Skills learned – Various forms of Animation (2D animation, stop motion and 3D modeling), Video Editing, Story & Character Creation, Storyboarding, Creative Direction, Directing, Audio Editing, Motion Graphics, Creative Problem Solving

- Graduated with Distinction. 3.93 GPA
- Recipient of several scholarships
- Commissioned by the President of the Institute
- Participated in multiple exhibitions including Columbia University and other venues

BA: San Francisco State University, San Francisco, CA

Major in Cinema with a minor in Animation

- Received jury award for film Vegetables
- Co-Directed Animation Finals showcase